<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Caffeine and Lasers - Book Reviews</title>
    <description>Book reviews and reading thoughts from Caffeine and Lasers</description>
    <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/Library.html</link>
    <atom:link href="https://caffeineandlasers.com/feeds/books.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <ttl>1440</ttl>

    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Negotiation by Max H. Bazerman]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> </p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Non-Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.com/Assets/book-covers/9780691249445.jpg" alt="Cover of Negotiation" style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p></p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/negotiation.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/negotiation.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[The Avoidable War by Kevin Rudd]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> 🟩</p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Non-Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.com/Assets/book-covers/9781541701298.jpg" alt="Cover of The Avoidable War" style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p></p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/the-avoidable-war.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/the-avoidable-war.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Being Human by Lewis Dartnell]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> 🟧</p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Non-Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.comhttps://covers.openlibrary.org/b/id/14748797-L.jpg" alt="Cover of Being Human" style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p>The book promises a lot, the concept is an investigation to how biology has shaped human society and history. For a while it manages to hold up to that promise, the first few chapters are genuinely really interesting. By the midpoint of the book it starts to drag unfortunately, while the first few chapters investigate where cooperation and altruism comes from, the middle starts to talk about how disease affected colonialism, and how cognitive biases lead to poor decisions in leaders. Important? Yes. Groundbreaking? Not exactly. 
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/being-human.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/being-human.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Exile Economics by Ben Chu]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> 🟧</p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Non-Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.com/Assets/book-covers/ExileEconomics.jpg" alt="Cover of Exile Economics" style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p>I probably need to stop reading books with theses which I already agree with from the beginning. Turns out that economic protectionism and isolationism is bad for your economy. Who knew?
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/exile-economics.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/exile-economics.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Careless People by Sarah Wynn-Williams]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> 🟩</p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Non-Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.com/Assets/book-covers/CarelessPeople.jpg" alt="Cover of Careless People" style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p>I knew Facebook did shady shit beforehand but the degree to which and the amount they knew that they were doing still managed to shock me. the metaphor the title implies, a reference to the Great Gatsby is extremely apt. The belligerence with which the Facebook leadership acted kind of blew me away. On the other hand, it is important to remember that this is and ex employee with an extra grind and she is bringing out all the dirty laundry. Personally, I tend to take a structural analysis point of view when talking about the problems with companies like Facebook. That Cory doctorow point about how the current cup of execs are not uniquely stupid or evil. They are just enabled by stupid laws. The book doesn&#39;t explore any of this, as far as Williams is concerned, the leadership at Facebook is uniquely evil and uncaring. 
 I remember when I had to study Great Gatsby in high school, we had to discuss the degree to which our narrator was a reliable narrator. Because he was enjoying all the same spoils as the people he was criticizing. I wonder about Williams. If she wasn&#39;t sexually harassed and bullied out of her job, I wonder how critical she would be of Facebook. Would she have still been a whistleblower if she wasn&#39;t treated so horribly by the people in charge? I don&#39;t know, maybe.
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/careless-people.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/careless-people.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[More Everything Forever by Adam Becker]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> 🟧</p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Non-Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.com/Assets/book-covers/moreEverythingForever.jpg" alt="Cover of More Everything Forever" style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p>This ends up feeling like one of those documentaries about flat Earth consspiracy theorests, except the nutjobs in question are Peter Theil, Sam Altman and Venture Captialists. I found it frustrating at some points because of the ammount of time it spends debunking obviously stupid ideas. It definately brought up some insights into ideology of some of these people, but the book felt a little bit too long IMHO. The ideology it describes is so incoherent that I find myself wondering how useful understanding it really is. If the actions of longtermist effective altruists are indistinguishable from a selfish asshole, then I wonder why not just apply Occam&#39;s Razor and assume they are just selfish assholes?
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/more-everything-forever.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/more-everything-forever.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[How They Get You by Chris Kohler]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> 🟩*</p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Non-Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.com/Assets/book-covers/howTheyGetYou.jpg" alt="Cover of How They Get You" style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p>*If you willingly read the finance stories in the news or know a bit about personal finance, you can probably skip this book. But I would highly recommend buying for any teenagers or twenty-somethings in your life. (I know I would have liked to have read it earlier in my life.) 

It ends up being closer to a personal finance book than an economica book. Its insights arnt really anything I hadn&#39;t heard before, BUT it is well written, Kohler is a funny guy, and it&#39;s lessons are absolutely important (I just happened to know most of them beforehand)

side note: this book also is extremely Australian and for Australian audiences. (a rare thing I&#39;m this world). by that, I don&#39;t mean he is talking about riding your kangaroo to school, but instead he discusses reasonable rates for you superfund and how pokies impacts Aussies specifically
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/how-they-get-you.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/how-they-get-you.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Challenger by Adam Higginbotham]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> 🟩</p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Non-Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.com/Assets/book-covers/9780241994269.png" alt="Cover of Challenger" style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p>It is embarrassing for me to  admit that I work in the  &#34;Space Industry&#34; but I barely know anything about space history, so I picked up this one.It was one of the most compelling non-fiction books I have ever read. It felt like reading a thriller. I swear I could hear the intense music kick in once I got to the chapter about the SRB O-rings. If you know you know. At a bit over 500 pages it is a bit of a commitment, but the breadth and depth of his reasearch was fantastic.
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/challenger.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/challenger.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Life As No One Knows It by Sara Imari Walker]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> ⭐</p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Non-Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.com/Assets/book-covers/LifeAsNoOneKnowsIt.jpg" alt="Cover of Life As No One Knows It" style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p>This was a great read as a physicist. The book was written with quite a high level of assumed knowledge, so if thermodynamics sounds like a scary word, I might suggest reading something more accessible. For me though, the premise was very interesting and prompted me to go and read a number of the papers cited in the book. From what I can tell, the central concept of &#34;Assembly Theory&#34; is somewhat controversial in Astrobiology circles, so I am not sure I am fully on board with the idea, but it is very interesting to engage with and think about. The book has me thinking a lot about the distinction between systems with selection, random systems and designed systems. I may have to write another blogpost about these ideas. Maybe one about Assembly Theory as well.
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/life-as-no-one-knows-it.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/life-as-no-one-knows-it.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sept 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Algospeak by Adam Aleksic]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> 🟧</p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Non-Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.com/Assets/book-covers/9781529949155.jpg" alt="Cover of Algospeak" style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p>I was maybe a little bit more educated than the target audience for the book, because I found a lot of the points made a little bit obvious, and I was waiting for new information. The book is well written however, and has a very nice flow to it. I listened to it as an audiobook, so even got to listen to Aleksik perform the accents he was describing. Aleksik seems to be more optimistic about our algorithm future than I am, and I am not sure he convinced me. (I may just be cranky and cynical however). The one point I can confidently state that I disagree with: I think Aleksik overstates the effect of accents, because I think he over-estimates the proportion of posters-to-consumers on social media. I cannot see how a micro-cultural accent can occur when the line of communication is mostly mono-directional.
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/algospeak.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/algospeak.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sept 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Snake Island  by Ben Hobson]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> 🟩</p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.com/Assets/book-covers/snakeisland.jpg" alt="Cover of Snake Island " style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p>The review they stick in the front describes it as &#34;Part western, part Greek tragedy&#34; and I think that is a really good description. The story is very Australian, but not in a cheap way, and all the characters are fascinating. I don&#39;t read a lot of fiction and even less &#34;literaqture&#34; but this was really enjoyable
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/snake-island.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/snake-island.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[I Spy: My life in MI5 by Tom Marcus]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> 🟧</p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Non-Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.com/Assets/book-covers/ispy.jpg" alt="Cover of I Spy: My life in MI5" style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p>Fair warning, this is straight up propaganda (it even had to pass MI5 clearance to publish) and is written like Tom Clancy. Nonetheless, it was really enjoyable to read. The narrative of it is mostly in the form of radio chatter which is a form I personally find gripping. Also kind of terrrifying to think how many terror plots get stopped, but it restored some level of my faith in instituitions to see the principaled stance that Tom and his team operated within.
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/i-spy-my-life-in-mi5.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/i-spy-my-life-in-mi5.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Everything Is Tuberculosis by John Green]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> 🟩</p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Non-Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.com/Assets/book-covers/978-0-525-42605-9.jpg" alt="Cover of Everything Is Tuberculosis" style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p>I never read John Green&#39;s YA fiction, since I was not a &#34;YA&#34; when I first came across it, BUT, I absolutely adored Crash Course History, and the way John thinks on Vlog Brothers. With this in mind, &#34;Everything is Tuberculosis&#34; is everything I hoped for. He places the diseases in the context of human history and present day human culture. He ends the book arguing that Tuberculosis used to be caused by bacterial infection, now it is caused by injustice, and it is our job to fix it.
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/everything-is-tuberculosis.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/everything-is-tuberculosis.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[No Power Greater: A History of Union Action in Australia by Liam Byrne]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> 🟧</p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Non-Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.com/Assets/book-covers/NoPowerGreater.jpg" alt="Cover of No Power Greater: A History of Union Action in Australia" style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p>A bit of a slog to get through to be completely honest, but also incredibly important. The book tells the story of Australia through the lens of union action. Turns out almost all the institutions I like were thanks to unions. If you have ever said the words &#34;Bob Hawke and Keating were Neoliberals&#34; you should read this book to understand how that period of history really worked
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/no-power-greater-a-history-of-union-action-in-australia.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/no-power-greater-a-history-of-union-action-in-australia.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 July 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[the happiness of dogs: why the unexamined life is the most worth living by Mark Rowlands]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> 🟩</p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Non-Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.com/Assets/book-covers/happinessOfDogs.jpg" alt="Cover of the happiness of dogs: why the unexamined life is the most worth living" style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p>this was a very accessible book on philosophy, i have previsoly struggled with a lot of &#34;traditional&#34; philosphy, e.g. netzsche and camus which who i&#39;ve attempted to read several times and keep bouncing off. admittedly, when i picked it up i was expecting a self-help book, turns out it was a philosophy of mind book. very worthwile anyway.
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/the-happiness-of-dogs-why-the-unexamined-life-is-the-most-worth-living.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/the-happiness-of-dogs-why-the-unexamined-life-is-the-most-worth-living.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 June 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Blindsight by Peter Watts]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> ⭐</p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.com/Assets/book-covers/blindsight.jpg" alt="Cover of Blindsight" style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p>Blindsight falls into the club with the Matrix and the Three Body Problem, of being a piece of Sci-Fi who is primarily a piece of philosophy. It is a ***crunchy*** bit of sci-fi which explores transhumanism more thoroughly than any other piece I can think of. I have more thoughts which I will save for an extended blogpost I think. 
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/blindsight.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/blindsight.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Conflict: the evolution of warfare from 1945 to Gaza by General David Petraeus and Andrew Roberts]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> 🟧</p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Non-Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.com/Assets/book-covers/Conflict.jpg" alt="Cover of Conflict: the evolution of warfare from 1945 to Gaza" style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p>This is a complicated one to recommend. It was a bit of a slog to read, and parts of it were quite confronting. Without going too much into my own political ideology, I don&#39;t think it would be that surprising to most that I do not agree 100% with the political opinions espoused by a general of the U.S military. That said, I do think it is worth a read. Not because I agree with all the opinions of the author, but because I think it is very important for many to understand how a general of the U.S. military thinks.
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/conflict-the-evolution-of-warfare-from-1945-to-gaza.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/conflict-the-evolution-of-warfare-from-1945-to-gaza.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[The Village Teacher by Liu Cixin]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> ⭐</p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.com/Assets/book-covers/theVillageTeacher.jpg" alt="Cover of The Village Teacher" style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p>Cixin does not miss. This short graphic novel which I read in an hour hit me like a sledgehammer with its final panel. Teachers are amazing. Go thank your nearest teacher.
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/the-village-teacher.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/the-village-teacher.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[The Trading Game: A Confession by Gary Stevenson]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> 🟩</p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Non-Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.com/Assets/book-covers/tradingGame.jpg" alt="Cover of The Trading Game: A Confession" style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p>I&#39;ve readlly enjoyed his Youtube channel &#34;Gary&#39;s Economis&#34; for a while now. In that light I was slightly disappointed that the book was mostly biographic, with not a whole lot of economics. That said, Stevensen is a REALLY great writer. Lots of very funny anecdotes, and insights. Worth the read.
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/the-trading-game-a-confession.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/the-trading-game-a-confession.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Technofeudalism: What Killed Capitalism by Yanis Varoufakis]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> ⭐</p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Non-Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.com/Assets/book-covers/Technofeudalism.jpg" alt="Cover of Technofeudalism: What Killed Capitalism" style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p>Varoufakis is a surprisingly great writer. The first chapter draws an extremely compelling extended metaphor between physics and philosphy and economics which blew me away. His core thesis is that we have moved beyond capitalism, and far from the socialist utopia which many predicted would be the downfall of capitalism, we ended up with something weird, and worse than capitalism. Very compelling read, and one of the more influential in how I currently percieve the world economy.
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/technofeudalism-what-killed-capitalism.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/technofeudalism-what-killed-capitalism.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Laziness does not exist: A defense of the exhausted, exploited, and overworked by Devon Price]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> 🟥</p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Non-Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.com/Assets/book-covers/lazinessdoesnotexist.jpg" alt="Cover of Laziness does not exist: A defense of the exhausted, exploited, and overworked" style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p>I found this to be less interesting than I hoped. Yep, if you work too hard you will burn out, and there are physiological signs. Idk, maybe some people need a book to tell them this, but I found it obvious and tedious
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/laziness-does-not-exist-a-defense-of-the-exhausted-exploited-and-overworked.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/laziness-does-not-exist-a-defense-of-the-exhausted-exploited-and-overworked.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[For the benefit of mankind by Liu Cixin]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> ⭐</p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.com/Assets/book-covers/benefitofmankind.jpg" alt="Cover of For the benefit of mankind" style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p>Cixin Liu did that really cool thing where he managed to thread the needle between a scathing critique of capital, while also criticising a reactionary authoritarian communist attempt at redistribution
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/for-the-benefit-of-mankind.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/for-the-benefit-of-mankind.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Bloom by Ruth Kassinger]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> ⭐</p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Non-Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.com/Assets/book-covers/bloom.jpg" alt="Cover of Bloom" style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p>This book is GREAT. It had me absolutley obsessed with a topic I previously knew nothing about. The book is covers the bilogoy, ecology and biotechnology of algea. It somehow had me turning pages faster I could have possibly thought given the topic. By the end I was obsessed and looking at ingredients on the back of boxes to identify the algal products inside.
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/bloom.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/bloom.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[War & Peace & War: 20 Years In Afghanistan by Andrew North]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> 🟩</p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Non-Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.com/Assets/book-covers/warandpeaceandwar.jpg" alt="Cover of War &amp; Peace &amp; War: 20 Years In Afghanistan" style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p>I really liked this one. It is a history of the last 20 years in Afghanistan, told biographically through the eyes of the authors collegues. This method of history is deeply personal, and I think an illuminating way to personally understand WHY things happened how they did in a sociological context.
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/war-peace-war-20-years-in-afghanistan.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/war-peace-war-20-years-in-afghanistan.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[In Ascension by Martin MacInnes]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> 🟩</p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.com/Assets/book-covers/978-1--83895-624-0.jpg" alt="Cover of In Ascension" style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p>A surprisingly humanist piece of Sci-Fi. This piece manages to both be both VERY accurate in the science, yet mostly interested in the humanity of is characters
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/in-ascension.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/in-ascension.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[How to Predict the Unpredictable The Art of Outsmarting Almost Everyone by William Poundstone]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> 🟩</p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Non-Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.com/Assets/book-covers/predictTheUnpredictable.jpg" alt="Cover of How to Predict the Unpredictable The Art of Outsmarting Almost Everyone" style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p>This one was really good. The central premise is that humans are really bad at true randomness, and we fall into very predicatble patterns while trying to do random. The book then outlines the mistakes we tend to make (and practical advice in how you could exploit those blindspots)
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/how-to-predict-the-unpredictable-the-art-of-outsmarting-almost-everyone.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/how-to-predict-the-unpredictable-the-art-of-outsmarting-almost-everyone.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[The Internet Con: How to seize the means of computation by Cory Doctorow]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> ⭐</p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Non-Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.com/Assets/book-covers/theinternetcon.jpg" alt="Cover of The Internet Con: How to seize the means of computation" style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p>Typically I am a very materialist (philosophically, not literally) person, and as a results this was one of the more impactful political books I have ever read. In many cases power is downstream from technology, and Doctorow expertly identifies the problems, their causes and their solutions. More than any other pice, this is a guidebook for the necessary changes to affect downstream changes.
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/the-internet-con-how-to-seize-the-means-of-computation.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/the-internet-con-how-to-seize-the-means-of-computation.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 July 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Froth: The Science of Beer by Mark Dredge]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> 🟩</p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Non-Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.com/Assets/book-covers/froth.jpg" alt="Cover of Froth: The Science of Beer" style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p>Of all the books I&#39;ve read about beer (3) this remains my favourite. Probably because it was written by a physicist.
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/froth-the-science-of-beer.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/froth-the-science-of-beer.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[The Three-Body Problem by Liu Cixin]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> ⭐</p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.com/Assets/book-covers/three-body-problem.jpg" alt="Cover of The Three-Body Problem" style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p>I never thought I would take &#34;Astro-socialogy&#34; as a serious concept before reading this. Read the whole series, seriously.
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/the-three-body-problem.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/the-three-body-problem.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Dune by Frank Herbert]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Rating:</strong> 🟩</p>
        <p><strong>Type:</strong> Fiction</p>
        <p><img src="https://caffeineandlasers.com/Assets/book-covers/dune.jpg" alt="Cover of Dune" style="max-width: 200px; box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.2);"/></p>
        <p>I read Dune, and Dune Messiah where it got a bit too weird. The original is where it is at. The book is at its most interesting when it is talking about real politik. 
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/dune.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caffeineandlasers.com/books/dune.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
